<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
                <title>Moon Toad</title>
                <description>Life and a Brush</description>
                <link>http://moontoad.net</link>
                <atom:link href="http://moontoad.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Make White</title>
                                <description>&lt;h1 id='make_white'&gt;Make White&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Titanium white and oil' src='http://moontoad.net/images/alchemy/2014-01-15-make-white/P1159231-web.JPG' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make my white paint every month or two. This is titanium white, chaulk and aged, purified linseed oil. The chaulk tones down the titanium and acts as a sicative. The oil is flax oil I purify with the water, sand and salt method of old. The paint is sublime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Lucious white paint and the muller.' src='http://moontoad.net/images/alchemy/2014-01-15-make-white/P1159232-web.JPG' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A muller is used to grind the paint. The action is not so much smashing as sheering the paint particles, breaking the clumps and surrounding each pigment particle in oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Tubing paint' src='http://moontoad.net/images/alchemy/2014-01-15-make-white/P1159234-web.JPG' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A syringe is used to hold the paint. This is the original ready made paint tube, in the mid 1800&amp;#8217;s the first tubed paint was sold in glass syringes. I use syringes because they are reusable and I came into a couple of boxes of them at some point. The best part is the precise control I have over the amounts of paint I can put on the pallette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Paint Making Finished' src='http://moontoad.net/images/alchemy/2014-01-15-make-white/P1159236-web.JPG' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 21:13:29 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://moontoad.net//alchemy/make-white.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://moontoad.net//alchemy/make-white.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Moon Panels</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Title' src='images/lunarem/2014-01-13-moon-panels/P7195889-web.JPG' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applying gesso and gold leaf to panels for the cycleum lunarem series.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 14:31:02 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://moontoad.net//lunarem/moon-panels.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://moontoad.net//lunarem/moon-panels.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Moon Sketch No.1</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Lunarem Sketch - Silverpoint 1' src='images/lunarem/2013-11-12-moon-sketch-No.1/MoonSketch1.1-web.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started a couple of Moon Sketches today, the first was fished out of the panel with silver point first and then finished with oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Lunarem Sketch - Silverpoint 2' src='images/lunarem/2013-11-12-moon-sketch-No.1/MoonSketch1.2-web.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the darks are blocked in nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Lunarem Sketch - Oil' src='images/lunarem/2013-11-12-moon-sketch-No.1/MoonSketch1.3-web.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second panel started straightaway with oil paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='First layer of Full Moon Paintings' src='images/lunarem/2013-11-12-moon-sketch-No.1/MoonSketch1.4-web.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while both paintings are to the point where they must dry before I continue, that is the first layer is finished. I think both will continue towards white and a dulling of the colors, a more monotone look all in all but these under layers will provide the pop for the final image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 21:52:27 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://moontoad.net//lunarem/moon-sketch-No.1.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://moontoad.net//lunarem/moon-sketch-No.1.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Yellow Mellon, Mud Wall</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Yellow Mellon, Mud wall' src='images/postcards/2013-11-11-yellow-mellon-mud-wall/YellowMellonMudWall-web.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple contrasts to brighten the day, can&amp;#8217;t wait to eat that mellon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 20:36:02 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://moontoad.net//postcards/yellow-mellon-mud-wall.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://moontoad.net//postcards/yellow-mellon-mud-wall.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>First Burn of Pennywood Stove</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Title' src='images/backpacking/2013-11-05-first-burn-of-pennywood-stove/PennyWoodStove1stTestLoadedwithwoodshopscraps-web.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loaded up the my first try at making a Penny Wood Stove with hardwood scraps and saw dust from my wood shop. Got it packed in pretty tight to limit the air draw. s &lt;img alt='Title' src='images/backpacking/2013-11-05-first-burn-of-pennywood-stove/pennyWoodStove-1stTest-web.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flaming pretty good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Title' src='images/backpacking/2013-11-05-first-burn-of-pennywood-stove/pennyWoodStoveAshProduction-web.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the water boiled I look the windscreen off and let the coals burn fast, the result was very little ash:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Title' src='images/backpacking/2013-11-05-first-burn-of-pennywood-stove/pennyWoodStoveOnFire-web.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to make some modifications for v2. I&amp;#8217;ve got too many holes in the bottom of the stove which makes the air draw to quickly. In turn this causes much bigger flames and I get less of a secondary gas burn then i&amp;#8217;d like. I also need to lower to pot level with some smaller stakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall though I don&amp;#8217;t see much use for this in backpacking except for in places that require a stove. The loss of the ambiance of a fire, the heat it provides and the long cook times it allows are just too important to our style of wilderness travel. We often cook indian food - dal and roti on the trail as it is hearty, tasty, cheap and light weight but this requires a much longer cook time then any stove allows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do have high hopes for this as a road trip tool though, I can just imagine the looks on peoples faces when we pull into a rest area and light up a wood stove to make coffee!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 11:19:55 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://moontoad.net//backpacking/first-burn-of-pennywood-stove.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://moontoad.net//backpacking/first-burn-of-pennywood-stove.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Water Canyon to Indian Creek</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;A hike through the San Mateo Mountains. Water Canyon to Indian Creek, about 17 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Mid Indian Creek, San Mateo Mountains, New Mexico' src='/images/backpacking/2013-10-31-water-canyon-to-indian-creek/midIndianCreek.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 11:40:04 -0600</pubDate>
                                <link>http://moontoad.net//backpacking/water-canyon-to-indian-creek.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://moontoad.net//backpacking/water-canyon-to-indian-creek.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Cinema Paradiso</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href='http://calvertjournal.com/slideshows/show/1481/independent-movie-theatres-russia-cinema-sergey-novikov,' title='A photographer’s ode to Russia’s dying movie theatres'&gt;aestetic&lt;/a&gt; gets me every time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 05:16:01 -0600</pubDate>
                                <link>http://moontoad.net//link/cinema-paradiso.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://moontoad.net//link/cinema-paradiso.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>The Hunter Moon</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The Original of Lunarem' src='http://moontoad.net/images/lunarem/theOG/theOG.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late Fall, the colors deep and the late light bending towards a pale fairness of a porcelin doll. Shadows deep and blue on the gold of a dying garden there is not much more food to be had from in there. The humming birds have long since headed south: searching with their knitting stick beaks for sweeter nectar than the stale offerings at hand in this desert land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rains progress is slipping away, the winds are back and the air has dried even the staunchest of mud puddles. Our desert was paradise for a moment, a moment which hung to the sides of hillsides and bottom of arroyos with clingin, needy arms. Give me water, give me water, give me water. Unsciable. A high school lust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above the &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Full_moon#Harvest_and_Hunter.27s_moons,' title='Wikipedia Hunter&amp;apos;s Moon Description'&gt;Hunter&amp;#8217;s Moon&lt;/a&gt; hangs defiantly to the wishes of the creatures fat from a long bountiful summer. Fruit gone the omnivores turn turn their heads towards flesh, the feast of the fall, the indulgence of protein before the cold takes root and brings brittleness back to bones. I hear at night the haunting yips of the coyotes on the mesa opposite our house. It&amp;#8217;s a lunarem lit affair, formal dining at it&amp;#8217;s most primitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I start this lunar affair: &lt;a href='http://moontoad.net/lunarem,' title='Cycleum Lunarem: painting the yearly lunar cycle'&gt;cycleum lunarem&lt;/a&gt;. A years worth of moons. A preview. A pedantic attempt at rigour and routine in my daily life. A disection of that heavenly sphere pulling at our hearts strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two acts to this process, the larning and the doing. I&amp;#8217;ve got to learn about the moon before I can paint it perfectly. I need to study it&amp;#8217;s habbits, i must stay up late at times, get up early others, learn the oceans of the moon, memorize the potmarked face like the back of my hand. And then, maybe then i can begin to paint it, to pull out the full history of the moon, that rock which shined bright on odyessues and the buddha. This sphere that i&amp;#8217;ve spend my three decades and change marveling after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll absorb my knowledge and share it back to the world. Then i&amp;#8217;ll paint, decisevely and steadfast out little satalite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                                <link>http://moontoad.net//lunarem/hunter-moon.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://moontoad.net//lunarem/hunter-moon.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
        </channel>
</rss>
